Yujun (Rachel) Yan

Portfolio: https://rachelyvj.github.io/my-website/

Github: https://github.com/vermouthyyj

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yujun-rachel-yan-4b7010195/

Summary

Solid academy background of algorithms and internet technology. Great passion for programming and problem-solving. Fast learner and open to exploring new technologies. Self-motivated, experimenting, and innovating developer. Have test-driven development experience in an Agile Team. Snowboarding and Longboarding lover.

EDUCATION

The University of Melbourne

Melbourne, VIC

Mobile: 0466210396

Master's Degree, Software Engineering (with Distinction)

March 2020 - Jan. 2022

The University of Melbourne

Melbourne, VIC

Bachelor's Degree, Computing and Software Systems

Feb. 2018 - Dec. 2019

Email: yanyujun666@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Boshantech

Melbourne, VIC

Front-end Developer Intern | React, Node.js

Nov 2020 - Feb. 2021

• Involved in the "Smart Shower App" Team, enabled the users to set temperature and water flow before taking a shower, the system is mainly oriented to the disabled

Maintained the front-end: Beautified the layout and appearance of the webpage as the client required Integrated the software and hardware parts: Read and modified JSON file from the Webserver (Hardware) Orderly management of self and professional conduct, successfully implemented the required functions required by the client

Xiaomi

Beijing, China

Software Testing Engineer Intern | Java, UI automator

Nov. 2018 - Feb. 2019

• Involved in the "Smart Music" Team, performed basic functional testing of a mobile app for Xiaomi devices which can automatically add background music to the video

Implemented automated testing by Java language: Included volume tweaking, kinetic scrolling, etc Used UI automator to analyse UI elements, read logs and reported bugs

Projects

Education Design

Front-end Team | React, Node.is, Firebase

March 2021 - Nov. 2021

- Agile development of a high-quality interactive educational application that enables children aged 10 to 12 to learn effectively and achieve mental growth
- Used ReactHooks (State Hook, Effect Hook, Ref Hook) to use state and lifecycle methods inside functional
- Followed **RESTAPI** design rules and parsed multiple data types into JSON in the responses
- Used React-Router to manage the dff erent React components path location and React UI libraries such as Ant

Genyus Roundtable

Front-end Team | React, Node.js, Firebase

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Agile development of an online peer-led-focus group which involves giving people with lived experiences of disability or trauma invitation and access to engaging in a bespoke community project
- Developed as a React application which created interactive UI's more efficient
- Imported the Ant Design library to ensure version control
- Imported the Calendly API so that participants could register for a Roundtable session through Calendly

Family Artifacts Register Program

Front-end Team | Vue, Node.js, MySQL

Aug. 2019 - Nov. 2019

- Agile development of the Family Artifacts Register. The goal was to support family artefacts and memories
- Updated the Trello and collected the tasks per week without any delay for everyone to check
- Beautified the front-end pages

Honors and Awards

- Student Ambassador Leadership Program Nov. 2021
- Information Technology International Merit Scholarship Feb. 2017

Licenses And Certifications

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Aug. 2021

Volunteer Experience

FEIT Student Ambassador Leadership Program (April 2021 - Present)

- Mentored secondary school-aged students in the Girl Power in Engineering and Information Technology program.
- Team leading in our high school outreach activities. Social media takeovers.
- Faculty of Engineering and Information Technology codesign working groups.